Finding Aid for [Lewis Cass Speeches and other publications, 1830-1856]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
[Lewis Cass Speeches and other publications] 1830-1856
Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866
1 linear ft. (22 items)
DA 2 C343 S742
Speeches and publications, 1830-1856, of Lewis Cass, democratic politician.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection is open without restriction.
Territorial Governor of Michigan, Superintendent of Indian Affairs, Secretary of War under President Jackson, U.S. minister to France, and Democratic politician.
Speeches and publications, 1830-1856, of Lewis Cass, democratic politician. Topics include, prosecution of the war and Mexico, extension of slavery in Kansas and Nebraska territories, railroad land grants and other internal improvement projects and foreign affairs. Some speeches were delivered in the U.S. Senate, other at various civic or ceremonial affairs.
Subjects:
Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; Slavery--United States--Extension to the territories.; United States--Politics and government--1815-1861.
- Speeches and publications
  - Address...before the association of the alumni of Hamilton College, August 25, 1830 (Box 1)
  - Discourse...before the American Historical Society, January 30, 1836 (Box 1)
  - Speech...in reply to Mr. Benton of Missouri, April 2, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Speech...on the bill providing for the prosecution of the War Against Mexico. May 12, 1846 (Box 1)
  - France, its king, court, and government, by an American (Box 1)
    (Third edition, New York, 1848)
  - Remarks...on the late French Revolution, March 28, 1848 (Box 1)
  - Speech...in the Senate of the United States, January 4, 1850 (Box 1)
  - Remarks...on the dissolution of the Union and the Constitution of California, February 12, 1850 & February 20, 1850 (Box 1)
  - Address...Delivered before the Kalamazoo County Agricultural Society on Friday, October 11, 1850 (Box 1)
  - Remarks...delivered in the Senate, March 1 & 3, 1851 on the River & Harbor Bill (Box 1)
  - Speeches...in the Senate of the U.S,, December 11 & 12, 1851 (Box 1)
  - The North American Fisheries. Speech, August 3, 1852 (Box 1)
  - Speech on Non-Intervention, February10, 1852. (Box 1)
  - Remarks on the bill making a grant of public lands to Iowa to aid in constructing certain railroads, March 15, 1852 (Box 1)
  - Speech on the Collins Line of Steamers, May 7, 1852 (Box 1)
  - Speech...on the Clayton-Bulwer Treaty. January 11, 1854. (Box 1)
  - Nebraska & Kansas. Speech...on the powers of government over slavery in the territories, February20, 1854 (Box 1)
  - Address...to the democracy of Detroit, November 4, 1854 (Box 1)
  - Speech on...Religious Rights of American Citizens Residing or Travelling in Foreign Countries, 1854 (Box 1)
  - Speech...on our relations with Great Britain, January 28, 1856 (Box 1)
  - Kansas -- the territories, May 12-13, 1856 (Box 1)
  - Speech...on the president's veto messages on the river and harbor appropriation bills, July 7, 1856 (Box 1)